Cosplay, you say?
Well, this isn't solely my decision to make.
I'm more concerned about whether it's okay
to put this out for the other students to see.
Dude, look at her!
What do you think, Hanyuu-sensei?
Her tits are huge!
She's kept this a secret until now, right?
Couldn't this stir up some ruckus amongst the students?
Ririsa!
Mikari-chan?
What the hell is wrong with you?!
You're in big trouble! Just look at the blackboard!
What?
Ririsa Amano-san! You're failing EVERY
SUBJECT! DETENTION TODAY!!
How the hell are you failing everything?!
I was totally focused on prepping for that event...
What's wrong with you?!
Wow, Tachibana-san seems really nice.
Yeah! We should try to talk to her more.
Five Rising Stars
Sensei!
Where's Amano?
S-she's in detention.
Really?! Of all the days she had to be gone...
It's fine...
Okumura, I heard back about your club status.
I-I already know we're out of luck.
Our report would've gotten
posted if we got approved,
and no one was freaking out about it today...
So there's a reason for that.
We got approved,
but they're not gonna make the report public?
That's what they decided.
Only the principal and the student council president
know you guys are cosplaying.
Feeling torn?
I guess... But it's fine!
We should be happy we get to keep the room.
Still, is cosplay really something
we need to keep a secret?
That's the million-dollar question...
But, it's more complicated than you think, Okumura.
They wrote this report knowing full
well what the public reaction might be.
They said they shouldn't feel embarrassed about it,
or need to hide it.
I see.
But, I'm still not sure that's right.
I don't think they would've gone public like this
if they weren't about to lose their room.
It'd be better for them if they
didn't have to go through that ordeal,
in my opinion.
But they knew that could happen,
and still decided to turn in their report as-is.
I'm a cosplayer!
That passion and determination convinced
me to sign on as their advisor.
So would it be right for us to tell
them they have to keep it a secret?
I just don't know.
Sadly, I don't think everyone will be
as accepting as they're hoping.
Have they considered those negative repercussions?
No...
I think they just assumed it was
one of the risks of going public about it.
As nice as it would be to allow
their decision to play out,
that's not a realistic course of action.
I know what you're thinking.
We're being too controlling.
We need to respect their decision.
They're passionate and determined.
As an educator, that fills me with joy.
It's no wonder we'd leap at the
chance to support their passion.
But, their fellow students may do just the opposite.
Some may tease them.
Others could spread gossip
about Amano-san online.
In the worst case scenario,
they could become the target of severe bullying.
That reaction might convince her to
give up her cosplay hobby altogether.
He really thinks our students are that cruel?
Our own principal thinks they'd bully her?
This type of situation is hardly unique.
You see, Hanyuu-sensei,
I made a big mistake early in my career.
I was young and foolish,
and for decades afterwards,
I blamed myself for it.
I told myself I needed that failure.
I ignored the pain and acted as if it was all justified.
But eventually, I realized something.
I never needed to experience
that failure to learn and grow.
What does he mean by that?
If I could go back in time,
I'd stop my younger self
from making that mistake.
I wouldn't just watch him "gain experience,"
not when I know how it affected him.
Some people might think
mistakes make for good experience,
but sometimes,
we make mistakes
that never help us,
that we regret for the rest of our lives.
As an adult who knows
that regret all too well,
I don't want any child to
have to experience it.
If students never made mistakes,
they wouldn't need their teachers.
If we truly want to show our students respect,
then sometimes,
we need to oppose them.
Of course, being older doesn't mean
we'll always make the right decisions.
But we should use our wealth of experience
to help guide them
along the best possible path.
When push comes to shove,
we need to keep them safe,
even if they hate us for it.
That is our responsibility.
So he acknowledges our decision,
but thinks going public is too risky.
That's right.
It's not because he thinks what
you're doing is shameful.
It's to keep you guys from getting hurt
by taking on more risk without knowing.
Yeah, we might've jumped to that decision
without thinking it through all the way.
Thanks for watching out for us.
You're more mature than I thought.
I'd like to hear what Ririsa thinks, though...
Excuse us.
Is now a good time?
I ran into her on my way here
and gave her the lowdown.
Amano-san said she's OK with everything.
Ririsa, and the student council president...
Thank you so much for all your help!
I just did what our manual told us
to do and finished up the paperwork.
I did some research on cosplay as part of our review.
You're free to do as you like,
but we do have one rule you'll need to follow:
you cannot possess or create
pornographic or R-rated material.
That's it.
D-don't worry, we won't make anything like that!
Yeah! And we won't...
Possess it...
W-we'll throw out all the offending material today!
W-wait, but it took you years to
build your collection, Senpai!
I should've known better.
As club president,
I'll do what's necessary for us to stay a club.
Senpai...
We're not asking this because
we don't like what you're doing.
We just want to avoid any trouble.
We're rooting for you, truly.
Keep up the great work.
Oh, right!
Doing all that research got
me interested in cosplay.
I'd love to see your costume sometime.
Our student council president is awesome.
A saint.
Maybe we should use the freed-up space on
the bookshelf to erect a shrine in her honor.
Otaku are so quick to pray to new gods...
But I'd do it, too.
W-well, in any case, we get to stay a club!
Senpai! I'm so happy!
Great job, guys!
Wait! I can feel your, your milky bits!
Why can't I hug you?! Let your Sensei in on this!
That's right!
You were Mayura-sama all this time?!
Y-yeah, kinda.
I get to cosplay at school,
and I have Mayura-sama as my teacher?
I've never been this happy in my life!
I'm dying of cuteness!
Senpai?
Hey, what's with the giant group hug?
Huh? Whoa!
Make room for me!
Old Castle! Joe versus Lustalotte!
FIGHT!
Sensei, why are you so good at this?
Oh, please.
I've been cosplaying Lustalotte forever.
I've gotta be good at her!
That's right!
Our Milky Succubus Queen Mayura
is the real deal!
"Milky" what? "Milky Mayura"?
Milky Succubus Queen Mayura!
Lustalotte WINS!
Sensei, did you really have to beat me
with a "touch of death" combo without looking?
Milky Succubus
So our new teacher is a legendary cosplayer?
It's an actual miracle!
I met her at an event ages ago.
She was basically a god to me,
You guys should really stop casually throwing
and now she's here!
around the words "legendary" and "ages."
Especially when I'm not that much older than you guys!
Huh?!
I'm 22! I just graduated college!
I'm only five years older than you, Okumura!
Yeah, and a tenth-grader is
five years older than a fifth-grader!
It doesn't matter when you're older!
You see married couples who are 47 and 42!
That's normal!
Married couples?!
So you think it'd be totally normal to marry him?!
Senpai, would you ever marry a girl like our Sensei?
Don't you think it's rude to
ask that right in front of her?
Quit stalling and answer the damn question.
What? Well, lemme think...
We like the same stuff and
can play video games together.
You're good at cooking and sewing too, right?
Yeah, t-that's right.
Wait, why am I getting so nervous?!
Am I his type, or not? Just tell me already!
But she's 3D, and that's a red flag!
It sure is!
Want me to sew your damn mouths shut?
grump
What is happening right now?
So, what kind of girl is your type?
Oh, well, she's gotta have angel wings...
She has blonde pigtails,
If what I heard is right,
is cheerful and sweet,
Tachibana is Okumura's childhood friend.
and can use healing magic...
Poor girl's got it rough.
Hey, Sensei?
You were going to give me
some sewing tips today, right?
Oh, yeah, right.
That's exciting, huh, Ririsa?
Your costumes are all so incredible!
I thought you'd commissioned them,
but you made them yourself!
Yeah. Back in the day,
you had to make your own cosplay.
You're already a pretty skilled crafter, Amano.
Oh no, not at all!
I'm totally self-taught.
Anything you can teach me about
crafting will be a huge help!
Really?
Let's start with measuring yourself, then.
It's important to have
the correct measurements
so you can make a pattern that fits your body.
I'll get my clothes out of the way!
Hold it! Is she always like this?
Yep, this is normal.
I'll step out into the hall for now.
You don't have to do that.
Just turn around.
For real.
Then you and I can hang out.
I promised the student council
we'd do things the right way.
We went through all that to keep our room.
I don't want to get it taken away again!
Okumura really is so mature.
He's so great...
T-those are her legendary milky bits...
Okay, you ready?
Yup!
Remember, you're up against the
proportions of the manga character.
You're never gonna
match their proportions,
so your real measurements don't matter.
Use pads and shapewear to increase your bust,
or binders to flatten it,
but be sure you're wearing them
I'd say both of you match their proportions already.
when you take your measurements.
Okay!
Once you've got your numbers,
look at your references and start thinking fabrics.
What materials have you been using,
and where do you get them?
I've mostly been using stretch PVC and faux leather,
sometimes poly twill.
I get most of my fabric from Yuzawaya.
That tracks.
You guys have it so good.
Back in the dark ages,
you had to go to Nippori to get any specialty fabrics.
I'll go there when I need to, but yeah...
Today we have all the colors we need for any cosplay,
but it was way more limited back then.
Goodbye,
hair cuticle...
Cosplay wigs weren't much of a thing yet,
so some people dyed their actual hair.
Huh?!
BEFORE:                                                             NOW:
I mixed 100-yen clear mascara with
eyeshadow to make my own color!!
It matches my wig
So many colors!
Thank god for affordable, vivid makeup!!
Makeup was expensive and limited in scope,
so some people made their own.
What?!
BEFORE:
I mixed 100-yen clear mascara with
eyeshadow to make my own color!!
It matches my wig
You couldn't get prescription color contacts,
so we couldn't look right at the cameras.
BEFORE
Is he taking
my picture?
Glasses fetish heaven!!
That's why you saw so many cosplayers wearing glasses.
And color contacts were expensive,
so some people chose their
cosplays based on what they had.
And there weren't online marketplaces,
so we'd go to bulletin boards to trade costume parts.
Manager
Upper management
says it's probably a no-go
Bulletin boards?
Not like the ones in real life.
We kept in touch over IM. Calling cost money.
Gotcha, I'll talk to to them myself
What's IM?
Things were way tougher back then,
but we all found a way to get our cosplays done!
Okay, let's talk about patterning a costume.
Club Trash
You're throwing out your collection after all.
Oh, hey. Yeah, I said we would.
I'm glad you're taking your job so seriously.
Thank you for everything.
So there really are people out
there who'll cry about porn.
Go ahead and laugh.
I'm just another weird otaku.
Rules are rules, but I do feel sorry for you.
Y-you can buy them again when you turn eighteen.
I don't know much about these things, but, uh,
once you're of age,
it's completely okay for
you to possess adult material.
Oh, Prez...
W-was I wrong or something?!
No, just...
Doujinshi only get printed once in small supply.
I won't be able to get these ever again.
Oh, I didn't know that.
Then I'll pray, too.
So, are you guys cosplaying today?
No, probably not today.
Oh, okay.
Wait, do you have any interest in-
I'll come by now and then to make
sure you're still doing a good job!
O-okay.
Did you say something just now?
N-nope, didn't say a thing!
Okumura, my lord!
Our darling Liliel is the talk of the town!
Really? I was too nervous to look it up myself...
Then you're missing out!
Okay...
Okumura, my good man.
Have you heard of the legendary Mr. Camera?
Is he a famous photographer?
He's not just any photographer.
He's Mr. Camera!
Okay, and what does that mean?
Sounds freaky!
People say that any cosplayer he
highlights is bound to become a star.
He's a legendary figure in the cosplay world!
T-that makes him sound like some creepy producer...
Nah, he's just a regular office worker,
and a good man.
Oh, okay.
He's been taking pictures of amateur
cosplayers for over twenty years,
so he's got an impeccable eye for talent.
He photographed the Heavenly Queens
back when they were no-name cosplayers!
Hell, he's the one who coined the
Four Heavenly Queens in the first place!
As such, his website, Mr. Camera's Cosplay Blog,
has quite the influence on the cosplay world!
So he gave himself that weird name.
Keep going.
Last night, he posted a new photo article,
with this shocking title:
"Make Way for the Five Rising Stars of Cosplay!"
The Five Rising Stars of Cosplay?!
You sure this guy isn't full of it?
This isn't gonna turn into Swordmaster Yamato, is it?
If it did, then you would be one of
the warriors being struck down!
Huh?!
Your darling Liliel is on this illustrious list!
With the concept of Rising Star!
Liliel reaches fifth place
She is?!
The list names cosplayers who came
onto the scene within the last year.
Sadly, this means Milady Magino was ineligible.
These Five Rising Stars were
ranked from top to bottom as well.
He ranked them all?
W-where's Liliel?
Number five! Impressive, no?
Number five? That's dead last...
Yes, but just being mentioned in a
Mr. Camera article is incredible, my lord!
He wrote:
Number Five, Liliel (name unknown).
At Yokosuka CosStream,
she drew a crowd rivaling Miss 753.
Her costume and poses are impeccable,
and you can tell she harbors
a deep love for the character.
Her choice of character and approach to
cosplay is reminiscent of Mayura-chan.
It's no wonder many have said she is
next in line for the Heavenly throne.
However, this is her second appearance as Liliel.
Continuing with her could prove boring.
And with how skilled she is,
there appears to be little
room for her to grow and improve.
Considering this potential stagnation,
I've placed her as number five on this list.
But if she keeps this up,
she could forge carve out a niche,
just like Mayura-chan did before.
What do you think, my lord?
I think he's full of shit!
My Liliel is the cutest in the world!
Okumura, my lord, this is an unbiased review!
Pray, take it as earnest critique!
Y-yeah, okay...
HMMMMM
But something doesn't feel right...
The ranking,
saying she's got no room to grow...
But, I'd be pretty happy if
he'd put her as number one...
Maybe I'm just salty she didn't rank higher.
Well, he's got a lot more to say about her,
so take a look at it when
you've cleared your head.
And so you know, my lord,
he only posted about
Number Five and Number Four.
Would you like to hear about his Number Four?
I remember this girl well.
She caused quite the stir!
School Idol Series Cosplay Event
School Live!
She cosplayed Coulia from the
phone game Cinderella Stars.
Her completely unwavering stoic expression
embodied the soul of her icy character!
As for the reason this rising star
caused that aforementioned stir?
Why, from the moment she arrived
to the moment she disappeared,
she said not a single word,
nor did she move a single muscle on her face!
No hellos, no calling card...
just an icy princess that some
might have taken as haughty.
Yet her single appearance has sent
Holy hell, she's the perfect Coulia!
Now this is cosplay!
ripples across the entire cosplay community!
Rising Star Number Four, the icy beauty...
NONOA!
Never have I seen a fresh-faced cosplayer
make such an impact at their first event.
I wouldn't say she surpasses our fair Liliel,
but I understand why he placed her fourth.
In either case,
for Liliel to only be fifth on this list of rising stars...
It truly speaks to the breadth
of talent in the cosplay scene.
How exciting!
I daresay this year's Summer Comiket
will be a sight to behold...
Hey, Senpai!
Wait, is everything okay?
Fifth?! Ohmigosh, I'm so embarrassed!
Someone wrote about me!
I hope my pictures look okay.
What do you make of all this?
What do you mean?
Wow, this girl in fourth is super cute!
What an angel!
You're not upset?
That she's... Ranked higher than you?
Why would I be upset?
I mean, read this!
They could see how much I love Liliel!
I'm so happy.
I-I didn't know they wrote that.
I hadn't gotten that far.
Whoever this is, they totally saw what I was doing!
Someone gets me!
That's totally awesome!
Being ranked fifth is just icing on the cake.
Ririsa's right...
Though I wish everyone also
thought she's the cutest Liliel ever.
You're right.
Cosplay's not a competition.
That's right.
That's what I learned at our last event.
Cosplayers all share the same love!
Yeah.
Speaking of events,
let's start planning for the next one, Senpai!
Hell yeah!
Fifth?
Liliel...
If I could get her to...
Can We Be Friends?